David Sutton

Interaction and Experience Development DavidSutton585@gmail.com 585.333.0677

PROFILE

My passion is working hands-on with businesses to facilitate innovation with a user-centered approach to development. My expertise ranges from User Experience Research and Design, Software Development, Gamification and Accessibility.

I am founder and director of Upstate UX, a large User Experience Network in Upstate New York, and Crashtest, an RIT institution based on instilling the knowledge and values of an iterative, user-first process for product development.

I have designed and executed well-received projects for Xerox, PepsiCo and Apple and Verizon. I can build anything, even in competitive, fast-paced environments with shifting priorities, and I take pride in helping create a truly collaborative environment.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

- HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, Markdown
- Wordpress, PHP, Apache, Jekyll, Hugo, Python, C++, Java, C#

UI/UX PRODUCT DESIGN

- Adobe Creative Suite (Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks)
- Sketch App, Framer, Balsamiq,
- Figma, inVision, Axure, Origami, Principal, Adobe XD

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

B2B SOLUTIONS DESIGN SPECIALIST - 2010-PRESENT

VERIZON AND OTHER LOCAL SMB ORGS

- Working directly with local businesses to find solutions and innovation opportunities in their processes and services..
- Provide strategic consultation services as a Subject Matter Expert on Accessibility, Gamification and User Experience.
- In partnership with Verizon, achieved top 2% supplier of connected technology in Upstate NY and the primary individual supplier for SMB clients in Rochester NY.
- Take on many varied responsibilities and utilize my human-centered design principles solve design and business challenges for high-profile client companies.
- Creating/maintaining websites and web applications for local SMB clients.

CONSULTANT IN UX AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT - 2013-2017 XEROX - UI/UX INTERACTION DESIGN - 2015-2017

UI/UX Design specialist at Xerox in Webster, NY in the Experience Design Group.

- Coordinate across departments and disciplines to shape the user experience across product's web and mobile interfaces as well as onboard touchscreen UI.
- Lead in many processes such as persona development, user research, and ideation processes, wire framing/storyboarding, prototyping and user testing.
- Translate strategy, business requirements and usability best practices into best-inclass digital experiences.
- Responsible for all design and functional documentation of my products including style guides, user experience standards, maintaining current and consistent UI and functionality across platforms.

APPLE - UI/UX DEVELOPER- 2013-2014

UI/UX consultant at Apple Inc. in Cupertino, California.

- Lead design and development of several new products, with a focus on rapid prototyping and web applications development.
- Managing a development schedule in a rapidly-changing large-scale development environment with shifting priorities and timelines.

EDUCATION

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY 2014

Concentrations in UX Design and Web Design & Development

CERTIFICATIONS & ASSOCIATIONS

IDEO'S "HUMAN-CENTERED DESIGN" CERTIFICATION

Implementing the core concepts of human-centered design to effect social change.

LUMA INSTITUTE'S "INNOVATION THROUGH USER-CENTERED DESIGN"

Leading a Culture of Innovation, Brainstorming, Problem Framing, Rapid Iteration and Product Testing, Prototyping, Ethnographic Research, Usertesting and Interpretation.

UPSTATE UX

Founded UpstateUX for designers, developers, and students to learn, teach & collaborate in Rochester.

 Workshops, conferences, networking events, Q & A discussions, professional development training and general community outreach.

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY & MONROE COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Instructed multiple courses on topics including:

- Computer Programming (HTML/CSS, Advanced Java)
- Front-end Web Development
- Interaction & UI/UX Design
- Facilitated and instructed the IDEO Design Certification Program for over 100 students and professionals.
- Founded & directed the nationally recognized organization "Crashtest", facilitating iterative, user-first processes for development.